Staudinger, Hans; Papers ger087
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Teaching and research materials, 1968-1979; Undated; 8
  - Germany - Economics, Undated; oversized (Box 18 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 28)
  - Germany - Politics, Undated; oversized (Box 18 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 29)
  - Germany - SPD, Undated (Box 19 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 1)
  - Germany - SPD - Socialism, Undated (Box 19 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 2)
  - Germany - SPD - Socialism, Undated (Box 19 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 3)
    Correspondence with Wilhelm Hennis.
  - Germany - SPD - Socialism, Undated (Box 19 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 4)
  - Human rights, Undated (Box 19 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 5)
  - Immigration, Undated (Box 19 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 6)
  - Import - Export (continued), Undated (Box 19 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 7)
  - Industry - Labor, Undated (Box 19 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 8-13)
  - Inflation, Undated (Box 19 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 14-20)
  - Law, Undated (Box 19 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 21)
  - Leisure time project, Undated (Box 19 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 22-40)
  - Law, Undated (Box 19 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 41)
  - Leisure time project, Undated; oversized (Box 19 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 42-43)
  - Leisure time project, Undated (Box 20 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 1-3)
  - Literature, Undated (Box 20 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 4)
  - Marxism, Undated (Box 20 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 5)
  - Money - Financing, Undated (Box 20 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 6-21)
  - Multinationals, Undated (Box 20 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 22-23)
  - Music, Undated (Box 20 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 24)
  - Old Age, Undated (Box 20 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 25)
  - Peace, Undated (Box 20 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 26-28)
  - Philosophy, Undated (Box 21 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 1-4)
  - Politics, Undated (Box 21 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 5-10)
  - Population Growth, Undated (Box 21 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 11-15)
  - Poverty, Undated (Box 21 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 16)
  - Psychology, Undated (Box 21 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 17-21)
  - Religion, Undated (Box 21 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 22-25)
  - Resources, Undated (Box 21 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 26)
  - Resources - Steel, Undated (Box 22 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 1)
  - Resources - Water, Undated (Box 22 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 2)
  - Socialism, Undated (Box 22 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 3-6)
  - Sociology, Undated (Box 22 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 7-8)
  - United Nations, Undated (Box 22 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 9)
  - Women and unsorted items, Undated (Box 22 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 10)
  - British-North American Committee, Undated (Box 23 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 1)
  - Canadian-American Committee, Undated (Box 23 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 2)
  - National Planning Association, Undated (Box 23 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 3)
  - Population Council Annual Report, 1968; 1969; 1970; 1972 (Box 23 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 4)
  - Inventory of Federal Population Research, Fiscal year 1973, 1974, 1975, 1976, 1973-1976 (Box 23 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 5)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions (various1publications), Undated (Box 23 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 6)
  - Congress of the United States. Notes from the Joint Economic Committee, 1977 March 14-1979 October 16 (Box 23 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 7)
  - Foreign Affairs, 1977 January (Box 23 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 8)
  - Various publications of U. S. Govt. Print. Off, Undated (Box 23 (8-Teaching and research materials), Folder 9)
- Writings, Undated; 9
  - "Die Anderungen in der Fuhrerstellung und der Struktut des organisierten Kapitalismus". (Festgabe für Gert von Eynern), Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 1)
  - "The Co-ordination of Public and Private Power Interests in European Countries", Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 2)
  - "Entwicklung und Form der Musikalisch-Geselligen Organisation", Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 3)
  - "Die Erwerbslosigkeit der Jugendlichen, ihre wirtschaftlichen Folgen und deren Bekümpfung, Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 4)
  - "The Future of Totalitarian Barter Trade", Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 5)
  - "Germany's Population Miracle", Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 6)
  - Individuum und Gemeinschaft in der Kulturorganisatin des Vereins, Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 7)
  - "Ist Amerika ein Wohlfahrtstaat-" (Festschrift für Joachim Tiburtius), Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 8)
  - "Leisure-Time and Free-Time Studies". (Festgabe für Alfred Weber), Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 9)
  - "Modern Tendencies in Public Utilities", Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 10)
  - "Die Neue Ceplante Wirtschaftspolitik der Vereingten Staaten", Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 11)
  - "Neue Perspektiven aus Wirtschaft und Recht", Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 12)
  - "Planning in Electricity", Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 13)
  - "Social Rates in Electricity", Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 14)
  - Der Staat als Unternehmer, Undated; typescript (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 15)
  - Der Staat als Unternehmer. (Published), Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 16)
  - "Der Staat als Unternehner". in Du und der Staat, Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 17)
  - State and Economic System. Lectures by Dr. Hans Staudinger. Delivered at the New School for Social Research, Undated; typescript (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 18)
  - "Toward a Long Range Power Policy", Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 19)
  - "The United States and World Reconstruction", Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 20)
  - Book review: re: Stolper, Gustav, Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 21)
  - New School Faculty -- Publications, Undated (Box 24 (9-Writings), Folder 22)
    Asch, Solomon E.
    Ascoli, Max.
    Aubrey, Henry G.
    Balinky, Alexander S. (galley proof).
    Brecht, Arnold.
    Doroghi, Ervin.
    Feiler, Arthur (including tribute on his death).
    Halasi, Albert.
    Hamburger, Ernest.
    Heidegger, Martin.
    Hula, Erich.
    Jonas, Hans - Johnson, Alvin - The Yale Review Autumn 1939, Winter 1939.
    Levi, Nino.
    Lowe, Adolph.
    Lachmann, Kurt.
    Marchak, Jakob.
    Modigliani, Franco.
    Moore, Wilbert E.
    Neisser, Hans.
    Rios, Fernando de los.
    Salz, Beate.
    Schutz, Alfred.
    Speier, Hans.
    Sternberg, Fritz.
    White, Howard B.
- Miscellaneous, 1933-1974; 10
  Oversized items; materials removed from books; artifacts.
  - White vase, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 1)
    (cracked and chipped) - Lettered in gold: zur freundlichen erinnerung an die gemeinsame Arbeit im preussischen Ministerium fur Handel und Gewerbe. Herrn Staatssekretar Dr. Staudinger. 1927-1932. Dr. Ernst Schultze Cossmann Flemming Schindler Romhild Dr. Schalfejew.
  - Bronze medal on green ribbon, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 2)
    "Founders medal - Graduate Faculty of the New School for Social Research". On obverse: "Presented to Dr. Hans Staudinger/Dean Emeritus and Professor Emeritus of Economics/Fortieth Anniversary convocation of the Graduate Faculty/New York City/September 25, 1973".
  - United States passport number D1441318, issued to Dr. Hans Staudinger, 1973 June 4 (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 3)
    (Contains photograph of Dr. Staudinger).
  - United States Certificate of Naturalization No. 4776622, petition no. 351696, issued at the U. S. District Court, New York City, 1940 September 26 (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 4)
  - Cross on red ribbon in blue box, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 5)
  - Blue box 5 ribbons (2 black and white; 2 gray and red; 1 black, white, and red)., Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 6)
    2 black crosses, W1914 (one on black and white ribbon).
    1 black cross (Für krieges - hilfsdienst).
    1 small red cross on ribbon and tie-tac. (on back of tie-tack: Steinhauer& Luck, Lüdenscheid).
    1 small red cross on ribbon and tie-tac.
    1 oval metal disk on red, black and yellow cord. Inscribed: Lt. D. Res.
    D. (-). H. W. Staudinger. Heidelberg. Unter-Fauler-Pelz. No. 2.
    16.8.89 J.R.III J.R.III Kriegsranclistten 199.
    1 blue envelope labeled Tapferkeits-Medaille. (with handwritten note added).
  - Citation, Undated; framed (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 7)
    Citation presentation of Graduate Faculty Founders Medal to Dr. Hans Staudinger... September 25, 1973.
  - Piece of embossed leather, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 8)
  - Envelope with handwritten note, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 9)
    I gave the honor crosses of the Republic of HST [Hans Staudinger] to my nephew Mark Staudinger. Could you send him or me copies of certificates. Here my (-) & World War I of my fathers decorations.
  - Biographical documents, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 10)
    (Heidelberg, Darmstadt, Munich).
  - Staudinger, Hans. Christmas letter, 1964 (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 11)
  - Neuaufbau der Absatzwerbung, 1933 October (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 12)
  - Leo Baeck Institute - W. Laqueur - The first news of the Holocaust, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 13)
  - Staudinger, Else - Passport application, etc., Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 14)
  - Staudinger, Else - Dissertation, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 15)
  - German articles, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 16)
  - Alvin Johnson - photograph, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 17)
  - Dampfkraftwerk "Staudinger", Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 18)
  - Photo-album: Grundsteinlegung Dampfkraftwerk "Staudinger", 1963 June 26 (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 19)
  - Photo-album: Grosskrotzenburg am Main, 1965 September 16 (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 20)
  - Photo-album: Aktiengesellschaft Obere Saale/Weimar, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 21)
  - Address book, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 22)
  - Darmstadt in alten Unsichten, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 23)
  - Box of bookplates, Undated (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 24)
  - Staudinger, Else - Cookbook, 1903 (Box 25 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 25)
  - Materials found inside Staudinger books., Undated (Box 26 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 1-5)
  - Doctorate - Heidelberg, 1963 (Box 26 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 6)
  - Broadside re Foundation, by Alvin Johnson, Undated (Box 26 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 7)
  - Staudinger, Else - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 26 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 8)
  - Alvin Johnson, Undated; photograph (Box 26 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 9)
  - Galley proofs, Undated (Box 26 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 10)
    "Public Utilities under Democratic Government"; "Die Üderungen in der Fuhrerstellung und der Struktur des organisieriten Kapitalismus"; "Germany's Population Miracle".
  - Duplicates, Undated (Box 27 (10-Miscellaneous), Folder 1)